[
    {
        "question": "How many books does the New Testament have?",
        "correctAnswer": "27",
        "incorrectAnswers": [
            "26",
            "66",
            "39"
        ],
        "difficulty": 3,
        "type": "mc",
        "categories": [],
        "biblicalReference": null
    },
    {
        "question": "What did Hannah name her child?",
        "correctAnswer": "Samuel",
        "incorrectAnswers": [
            "Saul",
            "Samson",
            "Gideon"
        ],
        "difficulty": 1,
        "type": "mc",
        "categories": [],
        "biblicalReference": "1 Samuel 1:20"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who was responsible for the infanticide in Bethlehem, shortly after the birth of Jesus?",
        "correctAnswer": "Herod",
        "incorrectAnswers": [
            "Pilate",
            "The High Priest",
            "Quirinius"
        ],
        "difficulty": 1,
        "type": "mc",
        "categories": [
            "Matthew"
        ],
        "biblicalReference": "Matthew 1"
    },
    {
        "question": "Jesus healed Peter's mother-in-law. What was wrong with her?",
        "correctAnswer": "Fever",
        "incorrectAnswers": [
            "Paralysis",
            "Blind in one eye",
            "Hemorrhages"
        ],
        "difficulty": 4,
        "type": "mc",
        "categories": [],
        "biblicalReference": "Mark 1"
    },
    {
        "question": "What promise do the meek receive from the Lord Jesus in the Beatitudes?",
        "correctAnswer": "They will inherit the earth",
        "incorrectAnswers": [
            "Theirs is the Kingdom of heaven",
            "They will be called children of God",
            "They will see God"
        ],
        "difficulty": 3,
        "type": "mc",
        "categories": [
            "Matthew"
        ],
        "biblicalReference": "Matthew 5:5"
    },
    {
        "question": "What promise follows the beatitude 'blessed are the pure in heart'?",
        "correctAnswer": "they will see God",
        "incorrectAnswers": [
            "Theirs is the Kingdom of heaven",
            "They will be called children of God",
            "They will inherit the earth"
        ],
        "difficulty": 3,
        "type": "mc",
        "categories": [],
        "biblicalReference": "Matthew 5:8"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which prophet was not allowed to marry by the Lord?",
        "correctAnswer": "Jeremiah",
        "incorrectAnswers": [
            "Isaiah",
            "Ezekiel",
            "Hosea"
        ],
        "difficulty": 5,
        "type": "mc",
        "categories": [
            "Jeremiah"
        ],
        "biblicalReference": "Jeremiah 16:2"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which prophet had to marry by order of the Lord?",
        "correctAnswer": "Hosea",
        "incorrectAnswers": [
            "Isaiah",
            "Jeremiah",
            "Ezekiel"
        ],
        "difficulty": 5,
        "type": "mc",
        "categories": [
            "Hosea"
        ],
        "biblicalReference": "Hosea 1:2"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which prophet and his children were a symbol for Israel?",
        "correctAnswer": "Isaiah",
        "incorrectAnswers": [
            "Jeremiah",
            "Ezekiel",
            "Hosea"
        ],
        "difficulty": 5,
        "type": "mc",
        "categories": [
            "Isaiah"
        ],
        "biblicalReference": null
    },
    {
        "question": "Which prophet lost his wife during his time as a prophet?",
        "correctAnswer": "Ezekiel",
        "incorrectAnswers": [
            "Isaiah",
            "Jeremiah",
            "Hosea"
        ],
        "difficulty": 5,
        "type": "mc",
        "categories": [
            "Ezekiel"
        ],
        "biblicalReference": "Ezekiel 24:16-24"
    },
    {
        "question": "On the 1st day God created...",
        "correctAnswer": "the light",
        "incorrectAnswers": [
            "man",
            "the plants",
            "the fish"
        ],
        "difficulty": 1,
        "type": "fitb",
        "categories": [
            "Genesis"
        ],
        "biblicalReference": "Genesis 1:4"
    },
    {
        "question": "On the 2nd day there was a separation between...",
        "correctAnswer": "sea and sky",
        "incorrectAnswers": [
            "sea and land",
            "light and darkness",
            "light and land"
        ],
        "difficulty": 1,
        "type": "fitb",
        "categories": [
            "Genesis"
        ],
        "biblicalReference": "Genesis 1:6-8"
    },
    {
        "question": "God rested on the...",
        "correctAnswer": "7th day",
        "incorrectAnswers": [
            "1st day",
            "5th day",
            "6th day"
        ],
        "difficulty": 1,
        "type": "fitb",
        "categories": [
            "Genesis"
        ],
        "biblicalReference": "Genesis 2:2"
    },
    {
        "question": "Where was the tree of the knowledge of good and evil?",
        "correctAnswer": "In the Garden of Eden",
        "incorrectAnswers": [
            "In the Garden of Aden",
            "Just outside the Garden of Eden",
            "In Shinar"
        ],
        "difficulty": 1,
        "type": "mc",
        "categories": [
            "Genesis"
        ],
        "biblicalReference": "Genesis 2 and 3"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who was murdered by Cain?",
        "correctAnswer": "Abel",
        "incorrectAnswers": [
            "His mother",
            "His father",
            "Esau"
        ],
        "difficulty": 1,
        "type": "mc",
        "categories": [
            "Genesis"
        ],
        "biblicalReference": null
    },
    {
        "question": "How old was Methuselah when he died?",
        "correctAnswer": "969",
        "incorrectAnswers": [
            "996",
            "966",
            "669"
        ],
        "difficulty": 1,
        "type": "mc",
        "categories": [
            "Genesis"
        ],
        "biblicalReference": "Genesis 5:27"
    },
    {
        "question": "How long was Noah with his family in the ark?",
        "correctAnswer": "Over a year",
        "incorrectAnswers": [
            "40 days",
            "7 months",
            "1.5 years"
        ],
        "difficulty": 3,
        "type": "mc",
        "categories": [
            "Genesis"
        ],
        "biblicalReference": "Genesis 8"
    },
    {
        "question": "The top of the tower of Babel was to reach...",
        "correctAnswer": "to heaven",
        "incorrectAnswers": [
            "the clouds",
            "great height",
            "an invisible height"
        ],
        "difficulty": 1,
        "type": "fitb",
        "categories": [
            "Genesis"
        ],
        "biblicalReference": "Genesis 11:4"
    },
    {
        "question": "What does the word 'Babel' mean?",
        "correctAnswer": "Confusion",
        "incorrectAnswers": [
            "Great city",
            "Great tower",
            "Corruption"
        ],
        "difficulty": 3,
        "type": "mc",
        "categories": [
            "Genesis"
        ],
        "biblicalReference": "Genesis 11"
    },
    {
        "question": "Where was Abram born?",
        "correctAnswer": "Ur of the Chaldees",
        "incorrectAnswers": [
            "Canaan",
            "Egypt",
            "Shinar"
        ],
        "difficulty": 1,
        "type": "mc",
        "categories": [
            "Genesis"
        ],
        "biblicalReference": "Genesis 11:26"
    },
    {
        "question": "What was the name of Abram's father?",
        "correctAnswer": "Terah",
        "incorrectAnswers": [
            "Lot",
            "Isaac",
            "Noah"
        ],
        "difficulty": 3,
        "type": "mc",
        "categories": [
            "Genesis"
        ],
        "biblicalReference": "Genesis 11:26"
    },
    {
        "question": "Why did Abram go to Canaan?",
        "correctAnswer": "God asked him to",
        "incorrectAnswers": [
            "There was enough work there",
            "His family already lived there",
            "There was enough to eat there"
        ],
        "difficulty": 1,
        "type": "mc",
        "categories": [
            "Genesis"
        ],
        "biblicalReference": "Genesis 12"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who was Abram's wife?",
        "correctAnswer": "Sarai",
        "incorrectAnswers": [
            "Rebekah",
            "Rachel",
            "Zilpah"
        ],
        "difficulty": 1,
        "type": "mc",
        "categories": [
            "Genesis"
        ],
        "biblicalReference": "Genesis 11"
    },
    {
        "question": "Why did Abram and Sarai go to Egypt?",
        "correctAnswer": "There was a famine in Canaan",
        "incorrectAnswers": [
            "There was a lot of money to be made there",
            "They were visiting family",
            "It was a command from the Lord"
        ],
        "difficulty": 1,
        "type": "mc",
        "categories": [
            "Genesis"
        ],
        "biblicalReference": "Genesis 12:10"
    },
    {
        "question": "Abram and Lot return to Canaan. Where does Lot go to live?",
        "correctAnswer": "In the Jordan Valley",
        "incorrectAnswers": [
            "On the coast",
            "In the mountains",
            "In Sodom"
        ],
        "difficulty": 3,
        "type": "mc",
        "categories": [
            "Genesis"
        ],
        "biblicalReference": "Genesis 19"
    },
    {
        "question": "Sarai remains barren. Who becomes Abram's 2nd wife?",
        "correctAnswer": "Hagar",
        "incorrectAnswers": [
            "Rachel",
            "Zilpah",
            "Bilhah"
        ],
        "difficulty": 1,
        "type": "mc",
        "categories": [
            "Genesis"
        ],
        "biblicalReference": "Genesis 16:3"
    },
    {
        "question": "Abram and Hagar have a son, his name is...",
        "correctAnswer": "Ishmael",
        "incorrectAnswers": [
            "Lot",
            "Isaac",
            "Jacob"
        ],
        "difficulty": 1,
        "type": "fitb",
        "categories": [
            "Genesis"
        ],
        "biblicalReference": "Genesis 16:11"
    },
    {
        "question": "What did Lot's wife do?",
        "correctAnswer": "She looks back as she leaves Sodom",
        "incorrectAnswers": [
            "She warns her husband Lot",
            "She stays in Sodom",
            "She does what God asks of her"
        ],
        "difficulty": 1,
        "type": "mc",
        "categories": [
            "Genesis"
        ],
        "biblicalReference": "Genesis 19:26"
    },
    {
        "question": "Abraham and Sarah finally have a son. How old is Abraham then?",
        "correctAnswer": "100",
        "incorrectAnswers": [
            "80",
            "90",
            "120"
        ],
        "difficulty": 3,
        "type": "mc",
        "categories": [
            "Genesis"
        ],
        "biblicalReference": "Genesis 21:5"
    },
    {
        "question": "Where must Abraham offer Isaac?",
        "correctAnswer": "On Mount Moriah",
        "incorrectAnswers": [
            "On Mount Sinai",
            "On Mount Carmel",
            "On Mount Horeb"
        ],
        "difficulty": 3,
        "type": "mc",
        "categories": [
            "Genesis"
        ],
        "biblicalReference": "Genesis 22:2"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who does Isaac marry?",
        "correctAnswer": "Rebekah",
        "incorrectAnswers": [
            "Rachel",
            "Bilhah",
            "Sarah"
        ],
        "difficulty": 1,
        "type": "mc",
        "categories": [
            "Genesis"
        ],
        "biblicalReference": "Genesis 24:67"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who succeeds Moses?",
        "correctAnswer": "Joshua",
        "incorrectAnswers": [
            "Aaron",
            "Caleb",
            "Elijah"
        ],
        "difficulty": 1,
        "type": "mc",
        "categories": [
            "Joshua"
        ],
        "biblicalReference": "Joshua 1:1"
    },
    {
        "question": "Where did Moses strike the rock?",
        "correctAnswer": "at Meribah",
        "incorrectAnswers": [
            "at Edom",
            "at Marah",
            "at Elim"
        ],
        "difficulty": 3,
        "type": "mc",
        "categories": [
            "Exodus"
        ],
        "biblicalReference": "Exodus 17:7"
    },
    {
        "question": "After ... a large part of Canaan is conquered",
        "correctAnswer": "7 years",
        "incorrectAnswers": [
            "4 years",
            "6 years",
            "9 years"
        ],
        "difficulty": 5,
        "type": "fitb",
        "categories": [
            "Joshua"
        ],
        "biblicalReference": "Joshua"
    },
    {
        "question": "After the death of Joshua...",
        "correctAnswer": "there is no longer a leader",
        "incorrectAnswers": [
            "his son succeeds him",
            "Judah succeeds him",
            "Eleazer succeeds him"
        ],
        "difficulty": 3,
        "type": "fitb",
        "categories": [
            "Joshua"
        ],
        "biblicalReference": "Joshua 24"
    },
    {
        "question": "What was Israel's first task after the death of Joshua?",
        "correctAnswer": "Fighting the remaining Canaanites",
        "incorrectAnswers": [
            "Finding a new leader",
            "The people were given a period of rest",
            "Finding water sources"
        ],
        "difficulty": 3,
        "type": "mc",
        "categories": [
            "Judges"
        ],
        "biblicalReference": "Judges 1:1"
    },
    {
        "question": "A long period after the death of Joshua, there comes...",
        "correctAnswer": "a judge",
        "incorrectAnswers": [
            "a king",
            "an emperor",
            "a prophet"
        ],
        "difficulty": 3,
        "type": "fitb",
        "categories": [
            "Judges"
        ],
        "biblicalReference": "Judges 3:9"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who was the first judge?",
        "correctAnswer": "Othniel",
        "incorrectAnswers": [
            "Ehud",
            "Shamgar",
            "Barak"
        ],
        "difficulty": 2,
        "type": "mc",
        "categories": [
            "Genesis"
        ],
        "biblicalReference": "Judges 3:9"
    },
    {
        "question": "Under the leadership of the first judge...",
        "correctAnswer": "the people begin to serve God again",
        "incorrectAnswers": [
            "the people begin to serve the idols again",
            "the enemy is driven away",
            "the people become rebellious again"
        ],
        "difficulty": 3,
        "type": "fitb",
        "categories": [
            "Judges"
        ],
        "biblicalReference": "Judges 3: 9, 10"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who are the most famous judges?",
        "correctAnswer": "Gideon, Samson and Samuel",
        "incorrectAnswers": [
            "Saul, David and Solomon",
            "Jephthah, Deborah and Barak",
            "Othniel, Ehud and Shamgar"
        ],
        "difficulty": 1,
        "type": "mc",
        "categories": [
            "Judges"
        ],
        "biblicalReference": "Judges"
    },
    {
        "question": "With how many men does Gideon drive away a large army of the Midianites?",
        "correctAnswer": "300 men",
        "incorrectAnswers": [
            "1000 men",
            "100 men",
            "500 men"
        ],
        "difficulty": 3,
        "type": "mc",
        "categories": [
            "Judges"
        ],
        "biblicalReference": "Judges 7:6"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who was the last judge?",
        "correctAnswer": "Samuel",
        "incorrectAnswers": [
            "Eli",
            "Samson",
            "Jephthah"
        ],
        "difficulty": 1,
        "type": "mc",
        "categories": [
            "Judges"
        ],
        "biblicalReference": "1 Samuel"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which answer does not belong. Samson is not allowed to...",
        "correctAnswer": "marry",
        "incorrectAnswers": [
            "drink wine or beer",
            "cut his hair",
            "touch a dead person"
        ],
        "difficulty": 1,
        "type": "fitb",
        "categories": [
            "Judges"
        ],
        "biblicalReference": "Judges 13"
    },
    {
        "question": "Deborah defeated the...",
        "correctAnswer": "Canaanites",
        "incorrectAnswers": [
            "Midianites",
            "Ammonites",
            "Philistines"
        ],
        "difficulty": 5,
        "type": "fitb",
        "categories": [
            "Judges"
        ],
        "biblicalReference": "Judges 4"
    },
    {
        "question": "Several judges are called heroes of faith in the letter to the Hebrews. Which judge is not mentioned in it?",
        "correctAnswer": "Deborah",
        "incorrectAnswers": [
            "Gideon",
            "Samson",
            "Samuel"
        ],
        "difficulty": 3,
        "type": "mc",
        "categories": [],
        "biblicalReference": "Hebrews 11"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who leads the people after Samuel?",
        "correctAnswer": "King Saul",
        "incorrectAnswers": [
            "King David",
            "High Priest Eli",
            "Judge Samson"
        ],
        "difficulty": 1,
        "type": "mc",
        "categories": [],
        "biblicalReference": "1 Samuel 10:1"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who is the first king of Israel?",
        "correctAnswer": "Saul",
        "incorrectAnswers": [
            "David",
            "Solomon",
            "Herod"
        ],
        "difficulty": 1,
        "type": "mc",
        "categories": [],
        "biblicalReference": "1 Samuel 10:1"
    },
    {
        "question": "Saul is... by Samuel",
        "correctAnswer": "anointed",
        "incorrectAnswers": [
            "crowned",
            "initiated",
            "baptized"
        ],
        "difficulty": 1,
        "type": "fitb",
        "categories": [
            "1 Samuel"
        ],
        "biblicalReference": "1 Samuel 10:1"
    },
    {
        "question": "But I hate him, because he prophesies nothing good about me, but evil. Who said that?",
        "correctAnswer": "Ahab",
        "incorrectAnswers": [
            "Micaiah",
            "Jezebel",
            "Baasha"
        ],
        "difficulty": 5,
        "type": "mc",
        "categories": [
            "1 Kings"
        ],
        "biblicalReference": "1 Kings 22:8"
    },
    {
        "question": "In what time does the story of Ruth take place?",
        "correctAnswer": "Time of the Judges",
        "incorrectAnswers": [
            "Time of the Kings",
            "Exile",
            "Time of the Prophets"
        ],
        "difficulty": 3,
        "type": "mc",
        "categories": [
            "Genesis",
            "Ruth"
        ],
        "biblicalReference": null
    },
    {
        "question": "From what place did Elimelech and Naomi come?",
        "correctAnswer": "Bethlehem",
        "incorrectAnswers": [
            "Jerusalem",
            "Cana",
            "Moab"
        ],
        "difficulty": 3,
        "type": "mc",
        "categories": [
            "Ruth"
        ],
        "biblicalReference": "Ruth 1:1"
    },
    {
        "question": "What were the names of the women whom Naomi's sons married?",
        "correctAnswer": "Orpah and Ruth",
        "incorrectAnswers": [
            "Orpah and Rebekah",
            "Ruth and Rachel",
            "Ruth and Rebekah"
        ],
        "difficulty": 1,
        "type": "mc",
        "categories": [
            "Ruth"
        ],
        "biblicalReference": "Ruth 1:4"
    },
    {
        "question": "What did Naomi want to be called?",
        "correctAnswer": "Mara",
        "incorrectAnswers": [
            "Martha",
            "Mary",
            "Miriam"
        ],
        "difficulty": 1,
        "type": "mc",
        "categories": [
            "Ruth"
        ],
        "biblicalReference": "Ruth 1:20"
    },
    {
        "question": "Why was Boaz so kind to Ruth?",
        "correctAnswer": "Ruth's devotion to Naomi touched him",
        "incorrectAnswers": [
            "He was in love with Ruth",
            "Because he was related to Naomi",
            "God asked this of him"
        ],
        "difficulty": 3,
        "type": "mc",
        "categories": [
            "Ruth"
        ],
        "biblicalReference": "Ruth 2:11"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is a kinsman-redeemer?",
        "correctAnswer": "A close relative who has the duty to help another member of the family",
        "incorrectAnswers": [
            "A close relative",
            "A close relative who has a lot of money",
            "A close relative who lives in the same place"
        ],
        "difficulty": 1,
        "type": "mc",
        "categories": [],
        "biblicalReference": "Ruth 3:9"
    },
    {
        "question": "What did Boaz give as proof of his redemption?",
        "correctAnswer": "His shoe",
        "incorrectAnswers": [
            "A clay tablet",
            "His ring",
            "His overcoat"
        ],
        "difficulty": 3,
        "type": "mc",
        "categories": [
            "Ruth"
        ],
        "biblicalReference": "Ruth 4:7"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the name of the son of Boaz and Ruth?",
        "correctAnswer": "Obed",
        "incorrectAnswers": [
            "Judah",
            "Mahlon",
            "Chilion"
        ],
        "difficulty": 1,
        "type": "mc",
        "categories": [
            "Ruth"
        ],
        "biblicalReference": "Ruth 4:17"
    },
    {
        "question": "Whose father did Obed become?",
        "correctAnswer": "Jesse",
        "incorrectAnswers": [
            "Isaac",
            "Ishmael",
            "Issachar"
        ],
        "difficulty": 1,
        "type": "mc",
        "categories": [
            "Ruth"
        ],
        "biblicalReference": "Ruth 4:17"
    },
    {
        "question": "Whose father did Jesse become?",
        "correctAnswer": "King David",
        "incorrectAnswers": [
            "King Solomon",
            "King Saul",
            "King Abijah"
        ],
        "difficulty": 1,
        "type": "mc",
        "categories": [],
        "biblicalReference": "1Samuel 17:12"
    },
    {
        "question": "How many wives did Elkanah have?",
        "correctAnswer": "Two",
        "incorrectAnswers": [
            "One",
            "Three",
            "Four"
        ],
        "difficulty": 1,
        "type": "mc",
        "categories": [
            "Genesis"
        ],
        "biblicalReference": "1 Samuel 1:2"
    },
    {
        "question": "What did the old priest think when Hannah prayed in the temple?",
        "correctAnswer": "That she was drunk",
        "incorrectAnswers": [
            "That she was praying earnestly",
            "That she was sad",
            "That she was tired"
        ],
        "difficulty": 1,
        "type": "mc",
        "categories": [],
        "biblicalReference": "1 Samuel 1:14"
    },
    {
        "question": "What did Hannah name her son?",
        "correctAnswer": "Samuel",
        "incorrectAnswers": [
            "Samson",
            "Gideon",
            "Judah"
        ],
        "difficulty": 1,
        "type": "mc",
        "categories": [
            "Genesis"
        ],
        "biblicalReference": "1 Samuel 1:20"
    },
    {
        "question": "What does Samuel mean?",
        "correctAnswer": "Asked of God",
        "incorrectAnswers": [
            "Man of God",
            "Comforter",
            "God gives"
        ],
        "difficulty": 3,
        "type": "mc",
        "categories": [
            "1 Samuel",
            "2 Samuel"
        ],
        "biblicalReference": "1 Samuel 1:17"
    },
    {
        "question": "Where did Hannah take Samuel?",
        "correctAnswer": "To Eli",
        "incorrectAnswers": [
            "To Jerusalem",
            "To Elijah",
            "To the temple in Jerusalem"
        ],
        "difficulty": 3,
        "type": "mc",
        "categories": [
            "1 Samuel"
        ],
        "biblicalReference": "1 Samuel 1: 25"
    },
    {
        "question": "What did Hannah not have with her when she brought Samuel to Eli?",
        "correctAnswer": "2 measures of barley",
        "incorrectAnswers": [
            "3 bulls",
            "an ephah of flour",
            "a bottle of wine"
        ],
        "difficulty": 5,
        "type": "mc",
        "categories": [
            "1 Samuel"
        ],
        "biblicalReference": "1 Samuel 1:24"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who thought Samuel was calling him?",
        "correctAnswer": "Eli",
        "incorrectAnswers": [
            "Hophni",
            "Phinehas",
            "the Lord"
        ],
        "difficulty": 1,
        "type": "mc",
        "categories": [
            "1 Samuel"
        ],
        "biblicalReference": "1 Samuel 3"
    },
    {
        "question": "What position did Samuel not have in his life?",
        "correctAnswer": "King",
        "incorrectAnswers": [
            "Prophet",
            "Priest",
            "Judge"
        ],
        "difficulty": 1,
        "type": "mc",
        "categories": [],
        "biblicalReference": "1 Samuel"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the holy city called in Ezekiel 48?",
        "correctAnswer": "The Lord is there",
        "incorrectAnswers": [
            "Zion",
            "Jerusalem",
            "City of God"
        ],
        "difficulty": 5,
        "type": "mc",
        "categories": [
            "Ezekiel"
        ],
        "biblicalReference": "Ezekiel 48:35"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which psalm is sometimes called the shepherd's psalm?",
        "correctAnswer": "Psalm 23",
        "incorrectAnswers": [
            "Psalm 1",
            "Psalm 25",
            "Psalm 42"
        ],
        "difficulty": 1,
        "type": "mc",
        "categories": [
            "Psalms"
        ],
        "biblicalReference": "Psalm 23"
    },
    {
        "question": "What do you call a male sheep?",
        "correctAnswer": "A ram",
        "incorrectAnswers": [
            "A male dog",
            "A lamb",
            "A ewe"
        ],
        "difficulty": 1,
        "type": "mc",
        "categories": [
            "Genesis"
        ],
        "biblicalReference": "Genesis 22"
    },
    {
        "question": "What instrument did David often play?",
        "correctAnswer": "Harp",
        "incorrectAnswers": [
            "Zither",
            "Flute",
            "Cymbal"
        ],
        "difficulty": 3,
        "type": "mc",
        "categories": [
            "1 Samuel"
        ],
        "biblicalReference": "1 and 2 Samuel"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who wrote the book of Proverbs?",
        "correctAnswer": "Solomon",
        "incorrectAnswers": [
            "David",
            "Asaph",
            "Jehoshaphat"
        ],
        "difficulty": 1,
        "type": "mc",
        "categories": [
            "Proverbs"
        ],
        "biblicalReference": "Proverbs"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the beginning of knowledge?",
        "correctAnswer": "The fear of the Lord",
        "incorrectAnswers": [
            "The knowledge of the Lord",
            "The instruction of the Lord",
            "The prudence of the Lord"
        ],
        "difficulty": 3,
        "type": "mc",
        "categories": [
            "Proverbs"
        ],
        "biblicalReference": "Proverbs 1:7"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is God to those who walk uprightly?",
        "correctAnswer": "A Shield",
        "incorrectAnswers": [
            "A Fortress",
            "A Refuge",
            "A High Tower"
        ],
        "difficulty": 5,
        "type": "mc",
        "categories": [
            "Proverbs"
        ],
        "biblicalReference": "Proverbs 2:7"
    },
    {
        "question": "With what should one honor the Lord?",
        "correctAnswer": "With possessions",
        "incorrectAnswers": [
            "With prayer",
            "With wisdom",
            "With sincerity"
        ],
        "difficulty": 5,
        "type": "mc",
        "categories": [
            "Proverbs"
        ],
        "biblicalReference": "Proverbs 3:9"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is more precious than rubies?",
        "correctAnswer": "Wisdom",
        "incorrectAnswers": [
            "Love",
            "Virtue",
            "Knowledge"
        ],
        "difficulty": 5,
        "type": "mc",
        "categories": [
            "Proverbs"
        ],
        "biblicalReference": "Proverbs 3: 13-15"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who should be saved?",
        "correctAnswer": "Those who are in danger of death",
        "incorrectAnswers": [
            "Those who falter",
            "Those who stray",
            "Those who live wickedly"
        ],
        "difficulty": 5,
        "type": "mc",
        "categories": [
            "Proverbs"
        ],
        "biblicalReference": "Proverbs 24:11"
    },
    {
        "question": "Wisdom is like...?",
        "correctAnswer": "a graceful crown on the head",
        "incorrectAnswers": [
            "a golden cord around the neck",
            "an ornament of knowledge",
            "a band of insight"
        ],
        "difficulty": 3,
        "type": "fitb",
        "categories": [
            "Proverbs"
        ],
        "biblicalReference": "Proverbs 4:9"
    },
    {
        "question": "From what should our foot be kept away?",
        "correctAnswer": "From evil",
        "incorrectAnswers": [
            "From the way of the wicked",
            "From uneven paths",
            "From the paths of death"
        ],
        "difficulty": 5,
        "type": "mc",
        "categories": [
            "Proverbs"
        ],
        "biblicalReference": "Proverbs 4:14"
    },
    {
        "question": "How many things are an abomination to the Lord?",
        "correctAnswer": "Seven",
        "incorrectAnswers": [
            "Five",
            "Six",
            "Three"
        ],
        "difficulty": 5,
        "type": "mc",
        "categories": [
            "Proverbs"
        ],
        "biblicalReference": "Proverbs 6:16"
    },
    {
        "question": "What does love cover?",
        "correctAnswer": "All transgressions",
        "incorrectAnswers": [
            "All covetousness",
            "All foolishness",
            "All hatred"
        ],
        "difficulty": 5,
        "type": "mc",
        "categories": [
            "Proverbs"
        ],
        "biblicalReference": "Proverbs 10:12"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is in the house of a righteous person?",
        "correctAnswer": "A great treasure",
        "incorrectAnswers": [
            "Love and faithfulness",
            "Understanding",
            "Knowledge"
        ],
        "difficulty": 5,
        "type": "mc",
        "categories": [
            "Proverbs"
        ],
        "biblicalReference": "Proverbs 15:6"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who will fall into a pit?",
        "correctAnswer": "He who digs a pit",
        "incorrectAnswers": [
            "He who shoots burning arrows",
            "He who is wise in his own eyes",
            "He who gives honor to a fool"
        ],
        "difficulty": 3,
        "type": "mc",
        "categories": [
            "Proverbs"
        ],
        "biblicalReference": "Proverbs 26:27"
    },
    {
        "question": "When does one find mercy?",
        "correctAnswer": "When one confesses and forsakes his sins",
        "incorrectAnswers": [
            "When one is a man of insight",
            "When one loves in secret",
            "When one does not harden his heart"
        ],
        "difficulty": 3,
        "type": "mc",
        "categories": [
            "Proverbs"
        ],
        "biblicalReference": "Proverbs 28:13"
    },
    {
        "question": "Where did Jesus grow up?",
        "correctAnswer": "Nazareth",
        "incorrectAnswers": [
            "Jerusalem",
            "Bethlehem",
            "Capernaum"
        ],
        "difficulty": 1,
        "type": "mc",
        "categories": [
            "Matthew"
        ],
        "biblicalReference": "Matthew 2:23"
    },
    {
        "question": "How many days was Jesus tempted by the devil:",
        "correctAnswer": "40 days",
        "incorrectAnswers": [
            "3 days",
            "10 days",
            "7 weeks"
        ],
        "difficulty": 1,
        "type": "mc",
        "categories": [],
        "biblicalReference": "Mark 1:13"
    },
    {
        "question": "On what should one build one's house of life?",
        "correctAnswer": "Rock",
        "incorrectAnswers": [
            "Sand",
            "A mountain",
            "Clay soil"
        ],
        "difficulty": 1,
        "type": "mc",
        "categories": [],
        "biblicalReference": "Matthew 7:25"
    },
    {
        "question": "Of whom did Jesus say: I have not found such great faith, even in Israel?",
        "correctAnswer": "The centurion",
        "incorrectAnswers": [
            "Peter",
            "The leper",
            "The man born blind"
        ],
        "difficulty": 1,
        "type": "mc",
        "categories": [
            "Matthew"
        ],
        "biblicalReference": "Matthew 8:10"
    },
    {
        "question": "Where was Matthew when Jesus called him?",
        "correctAnswer": "In the tax collector's booth",
        "incorrectAnswers": [
            "On the temple square",
            "In a tree",
            "In front of his house"
        ],
        "difficulty": 3,
        "type": "mc",
        "categories": [
            "Matthew"
        ],
        "biblicalReference": "Matthew 9:9"
    },
    {
        "question": "How great must our faith be according to Jesus?",
        "correctAnswer": "Like a mustard seed",
        "incorrectAnswers": [
            "Like a mountain",
            "Like a rock",
            "Like a cedar of Lebanon"
        ],
        "difficulty": 1,
        "type": "mc",
        "categories": [
            "Matthew"
        ],
        "biblicalReference": "Matthew 17:20"
    },
    {
        "question": "How many times should we forgive each other?",
        "correctAnswer": "70 x 7 times",
        "incorrectAnswers": [
            "7 times",
            "3 times",
            "always"
        ],
        "difficulty": 1,
        "type": "mc",
        "categories": [],
        "biblicalReference": "Matthew 18:22"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who cried out: Lord, Son of David, have mercy on us?",
        "correctAnswer": "2 blind men",
        "incorrectAnswers": [
            "10 lepers",
            "the children",
            "the lame"
        ],
        "difficulty": 1,
        "type": "mc",
        "categories": [],
        "biblicalReference": "Matthew 20:30"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which tree was cursed by Jesus?",
        "correctAnswer": "The fig tree",
        "incorrectAnswers": [
            "The olive tree",
            "The cedar",
            "The date palm"
        ],
        "difficulty": 3,
        "type": "mc",
        "categories": [],
        "biblicalReference": "Mark 11:21"
    },
    {
        "question": "By whom was the book of Revelation written?",
        "correctAnswer": "John",
        "incorrectAnswers": [
            "Paul",
            "Peter",
            "Matthew"
        ],
        "difficulty": 1,
        "type": "mc",
        "categories": [
            "Revelation"
        ],
        "biblicalReference": "Revelation 1:1"
    },
    {
        "question": "To how many churches did John write a letter?",
        "correctAnswer": "7",
        "incorrectAnswers": [
            "6",
            "8",
            "5"
        ],
        "difficulty": 1,
        "type": "mc",
        "categories": [
            "Revelation"
        ],
        "biblicalReference": "Revelation"
    },
    {
        "question": "What was John to write to Ephesus?",
        "correctAnswer": "You have forsaken your first love",
        "incorrectAnswers": [
            "Be faithful unto death",
            "I have given you an open door",
            "And I will give to each of you according to your works"
        ],
        "difficulty": 5,
        "type": "mc",
        "categories": [
            "Ephesians"
        ],
        "biblicalReference": "Revelation 2:4"
    },
    {
        "question": "What will Jesus give to the church at Smyrna if they are faithful?",
        "correctAnswer": "The crown of life",
        "incorrectAnswers": [
            "A white stone",
            "A new name",
            "The hidden manna"
        ],
        "difficulty": 5,
        "type": "mc",
        "categories": [
            "Revelation"
        ],
        "biblicalReference": "Revelation 2:10"
    },
    {
        "question": "What teaching did they hold to in Pergamum?",
        "correctAnswer": "The teaching of Balaam",
        "incorrectAnswers": [
            "The teaching of the Pharisees",
            "There is no resurrection",
            "The teaching of Paul"
        ],
        "difficulty": 5,
        "type": "mc",
        "categories": [
            "Revelation"
        ],
        "biblicalReference": "Revelation 2:14"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which woman did they let go in Thyatira?",
        "correctAnswer": "Jezebel",
        "incorrectAnswers": [
            "the wife of Herod",
            "Potiphar's wife",
            "Salome"
        ],
        "difficulty": 5,
        "type": "mc",
        "categories": [
            "Revelation"
        ],
        "biblicalReference": "Revelation 2: 20-23"
    },
    {
        "question": "From what will Jesus keep the church of Philadelphia?",
        "correctAnswer": "The hour of trial",
        "incorrectAnswers": [
            "From poverty",
            "From diseases",
            "From spiritual decline"
        ],
        "difficulty": 5,
        "type": "mc",
        "categories": [
            "Revelation"
        ],
        "biblicalReference": "Revelation 3:10"
    },
    {
        "question": "Why will Jesus spit Laodicea out of his mouth?",
        "correctAnswer": "Because they are lukewarm",
        "incorrectAnswers": [
            "Because they are hot",
            "Because they are cold",
            "Because they are hard"
        ],
        "difficulty": 3,
        "type": "mc",
        "categories": [
            "Revelation"
        ],
        "biblicalReference": "Revelation 3: 15, 16"
    },
    {
        "question": "What was around the throne of God in Revelation?",
        "correctAnswer": "A rainbow",
        "incorrectAnswers": [
            "A light",
            "Golden rays",
            "A cloud"
        ],
        "difficulty": 5,
        "type": "mc",
        "categories": [
            "Revelation"
        ],
        "biblicalReference": "Revelation 4:3"
    },
    {
        "question": "And around the throne were thrones; and on the thrones I saw... elders sitting, clothed in white garments, and they had golden crowns on their heads.",
        "correctAnswer": "24",
        "incorrectAnswers": [
            "7",
            "7 x 7",
            "3"
        ],
        "difficulty": 3,
        "type": "fitb",
        "categories": [
            "Revelation"
        ],
        "biblicalReference": "Revelation 4:4"
    },
    {
        "question": "What did the crowd that no one could count have in its hand?",
        "correctAnswer": "Palm branches",
        "incorrectAnswers": [
            "Torches",
            "Trumpets",
            "Bowls of incense"
        ],
        "difficulty": 5,
        "type": "mc",
        "categories": [
            "Revelation"
        ],
        "biblicalReference": "Revelation 7:9"
    },
    {
        "question": "What does God do with the people who come out of the great tribulation?",
        "correctAnswer": "God will wipe away every tear from their eyes",
        "incorrectAnswers": [
            "God will give them a new name",
            "God will seal their foreheads",
            "God will dwell with them"
        ],
        "difficulty": 3,
        "type": "mc",
        "categories": [
            "Revelation"
        ],
        "biblicalReference": "Revelation 21:4"
    },
    {
        "question": "What happened when the third angel sounded his trumpet?",
        "correctAnswer": "A great star, burning like a torch, fell from heaven",
        "incorrectAnswers": [
            "The smoke of the incense with the prayers of the saints went up",
            "There was hail and fire mixed with blood",
            "Something like a great mountain, burning with fire, was thrown into the sea"
        ],
        "difficulty": 5,
        "type": "mc",
        "categories": [
            "Revelation"
        ],
        "biblicalReference": "Revelation 8:10"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the name of the angel of the abyss in Revelation?",
        "correctAnswer": "Abaddon",
        "incorrectAnswers": [
            "Lucifer",
            "The dragon",
            "The Beast"
        ],
        "difficulty": 5,
        "type": "mc",
        "categories": [
            "Revelation"
        ],
        "biblicalReference": "Revelation 9:11"
    },
    {
        "question": "What did John have to eat in Revelation?",
        "correctAnswer": "A little book",
        "incorrectAnswers": [
            "A honeycomb",
            "Bread",
            "Figs"
        ],
        "difficulty": 5,
        "type": "mc",
        "categories": [
            "Revelation"
        ],
        "biblicalReference": "Revelation 10:9"
    },
    {
        "question": "How many witnesses will prophesy for 1260 days?",
        "correctAnswer": "2",
        "incorrectAnswers": [
            "3",
            "7",
            "12"
        ],
        "difficulty": 5,
        "type": "mc",
        "categories": [
            "Revelation"
        ],
        "biblicalReference": "Revelation 11: 3-12"
    },
    {
        "question": "And the woman fled into the..., where she had a place prepared by God",
        "correctAnswer": "wilderness",
        "incorrectAnswers": [
            "temple",
            "mountains",
            "city"
        ],
        "difficulty": 3,
        "type": "fitb",
        "categories": [
            "Revelation"
        ],
        "biblicalReference": "Revelation 12:6"
    },
    {
        "question": "How many vials of wrath are there?",
        "correctAnswer": "Seven",
        "incorrectAnswers": [
            "Three",
            "Five",
            "Four"
        ],
        "difficulty": 5,
        "type": "mc",
        "categories": [
            "Revelation"
        ],
        "biblicalReference": "Revelation 16"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which city descends from heaven?",
        "correctAnswer": "The new Jerusalem",
        "incorrectAnswers": [
            "The city of God",
            "The city with many mansions",
            "That city which has foundations"
        ],
        "difficulty": 1,
        "type": "mc",
        "categories": [
            "Revelation"
        ],
        "biblicalReference": "Revelation 21: 1-4"
    },
    {
        "question": "What do the Spirit and the Bride say?",
        "correctAnswer": "Come",
        "incorrectAnswers": [
            "Amen",
            "Hallelujah",
            "I am the Alpha and the Omega"
        ],
        "difficulty": 1,
        "type": "mc",
        "categories": [
            "Revelation"
        ],
        "biblicalReference": "Revelation 22:17"
    },
    {
        "question": "How many letters are there from Paul to the Corinthians?",
        "correctAnswer": "Two",
        "incorrectAnswers": [
            "One",
            "Three",
            "Four"
        ],
        "difficulty": 1,
        "type": "mc",
        "categories": [
            "1 Corinthians",
            "2 Corinthians"
        ],
        "biblicalReference": "1 and 2 Corinthians"
    },
    {
        "question": "How many people did Jesus raise from the dead?",
        "correctAnswer": "Three",
        "incorrectAnswers": [
            "Two",
            "One",
            "Four"
        ],
        "difficulty": 3,
        "type": "mc",
        "categories": [],
        "biblicalReference": "Gospels"
    },
    {
        "question": "For about how many years did Jesus preach?",
        "correctAnswer": "Three",
        "incorrectAnswers": [
            "Two",
            "One",
            "Four"
        ],
        "difficulty": 1,
        "type": "mc",
        "categories": [],
        "biblicalReference": "In the Gospels"
    },
    {
        "question": "In what place did they drive Jesus out of the city, to the brow of the hill, to throw Him down into the abyss?",
        "correctAnswer": "Nazareth",
        "incorrectAnswers": [
            "Jerusalem",
            "Bethlehem",
            "Samaria"
        ],
        "difficulty": 1,
        "type": "mc",
        "categories": [],
        "biblicalReference": "Luke 4:29"
    },
    {
        "question": "In what place was Bartimaeus begging by the gate?",
        "correctAnswer": "Jericho",
        "incorrectAnswers": [
            "Jerusalem",
            "Samaria",
            "Capernaum"
        ],
        "difficulty": 3,
        "type": "mc",
        "categories": [],
        "biblicalReference": "Mark 10:46"
    },
    {
        "question": "To whom was it asked: Do you understand what you are reading?",
        "correctAnswer": "The Ethiopian eunuch",
        "incorrectAnswers": [
            "Philip",
            "Peter",
            "Saul"
        ],
        "difficulty": 1,
        "type": "mc",
        "categories": [
            "Acts"
        ],
        "biblicalReference": "Acts 8:30"
    },
    {
        "question": "What island did Paul and Barnabas visit on their first missionary journey?",
        "correctAnswer": "Cyprus",
        "incorrectAnswers": [
            "Crete",
            "Malta",
            "Sicily"
        ],
        "difficulty": 3,
        "type": "mc",
        "categories": [
            "Acts"
        ],
        "biblicalReference": "Acts 13:4"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which king had a serious, fatal illness?",
        "correctAnswer": "Hezekiah",
        "incorrectAnswers": [
            "Ahaz",
            "Manasseh",
            "Judah"
        ],
        "difficulty": 1,
        "type": "mc",
        "categories": [],
        "biblicalReference": "Hezekiah 20:1"
    },
    {
        "question": "After his flight from Queen Jezebel, Elijah fled to the cave. Which one?",
        "correctAnswer": "The cave on Mount Horeb",
        "incorrectAnswers": [
            "The cave of Machpelah",
            "The cave of Adullam",
            "The caves of Zephaniah"
        ],
        "difficulty": 3,
        "type": "mc",
        "categories": [
            "1 Kings"
        ],
        "biblicalReference": "1 Kings 19"
    },
    {
        "question": "What did the Israelites not take from the Egyptians at the exodus from Egypt?",
        "correctAnswer": "Food",
        "incorrectAnswers": [
            "Gold",
            "Silver",
            "Clothing"
        ],
        "difficulty": 3,
        "type": "mc",
        "categories": [
            "Exodus"
        ],
        "biblicalReference": "Exodus 3:22"
    },
    {
        "question": "How long was Paul imprisoned in Caesarea during the time of Felix and Festus?",
        "correctAnswer": "2 years",
        "incorrectAnswers": [
            "1.5 years",
            "2.5 years",
            "3 years"
        ],
        "difficulty": 3,
        "type": "mc",
        "categories": [
            "Acts"
        ],
        "biblicalReference": "Acts"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which deacon was stoned in Jerusalem?",
        "correctAnswer": "Stephen",
        "incorrectAnswers": [
            "Philip",
            "Timon",
            "Nicolas"
        ],
        "difficulty": 1,
        "type": "mc",
        "categories": [
            "Acts"
        ],
        "biblicalReference": "Acts 7: 54 - 60"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which son wanted to overthrow David from the throne?",
        "correctAnswer": "Absalom",
        "incorrectAnswers": [
            "Joab",
            "Amnon",
            "Adonijah"
        ],
        "difficulty": 1,
        "type": "mc",
        "categories": [
            "2 Samuel"
        ],
        "biblicalReference": "2 Samuel 15"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who were the first to visit Jesus after his birth?",
        "correctAnswer": "The shepherds",
        "incorrectAnswers": [
            "The wise men",
            "King Herod",
            "Zechariah and Elizabeth"
        ],
        "difficulty": 1,
        "type": "mc",
        "categories": [],
        "biblicalReference": "Luke 2: 8-20"
    },
    {
        "question": "10 lepers were healed by Jesus. Who came back to thank Him?",
        "correctAnswer": "A Samaritan",
        "incorrectAnswers": [
            "An Israelite",
            "A Jew",
            "A tax collector"
        ],
        "difficulty": 3,
        "type": "mc",
        "categories": [
            "Luke"
        ],
        "biblicalReference": "Luke 17: 11-19"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who was king when Daniel was thrown into the lions' den?",
        "correctAnswer": "Darius",
        "incorrectAnswers": [
            "Nebuchadnezzar",
            "Belshazzar",
            "Cyrus"
        ],
        "difficulty": 3,
        "type": "mc",
        "categories": [
            "Daniel"
        ],
        "biblicalReference": "Daniel 6"
    },
    {
        "question": "Peter's mother-in-law was healed of a fever. In what place was this?",
        "correctAnswer": "Capernaum",
        "incorrectAnswers": [
            "Cana",
            "Nain",
            "Jericho"
        ],
        "difficulty": 3,
        "type": "mc",
        "categories": [],
        "biblicalReference": "Matthew 8:14"
    },
    {
        "question": "The inhabitants of the Ten-Tribe Kingdom were carried away to...",
        "correctAnswer": "Assyria",
        "incorrectAnswers": [
            "Babel",
            "Persia",
            "Egypt"
        ],
        "difficulty": 3,
        "type": "fitb",
        "categories": [
            "2 Kings"
        ],
        "biblicalReference": "2 Kings 17:6"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which 2 tribes made up the two-tribe kingdom?",
        "correctAnswer": "Judah and Benjamin",
        "incorrectAnswers": [
            "Levi and Judah",
            "Joseph and Benjamin",
            "Judah and Levi"
        ],
        "difficulty": 3,
        "type": "mc",
        "categories": [
            "1 Kings"
        ],
        "biblicalReference": "1 Kings 12:21"
    },
    {
        "question": "3 names are for the same lake/sea. Which one does not belong?",
        "correctAnswer": "The Dead Sea",
        "incorrectAnswers": [
            "Sea of Galilee",
            "Lake of Gennesaret",
            "Sea of Tiberias"
        ],
        "difficulty": 1,
        "type": "mc",
        "categories": [],
        "biblicalReference": "In the Gospels"
    },
    {
        "question": "A new apostle was chosen in place of Judas. Who was that?",
        "correctAnswer": "Matthias",
        "incorrectAnswers": [
            "Justus",
            "Philip",
            "Nathanael"
        ],
        "difficulty": 3,
        "type": "mc",
        "categories": [
            "Acts"
        ],
        "biblicalReference": "Acts 1:26"
    },
    {
        "question": "What do we think of at Easter?",
        "correctAnswer": "The resurrection of Jesus",
        "incorrectAnswers": [
            "The birth of Jesus",
            "The death of Jesus",
            "The ascension of Jesus"
        ],
        "difficulty": 1,
        "type": "mc",
        "categories": [],
        "biblicalReference": "Mark 16"
    },
    {
        "question": "Daniel was given a Babylonian name. Which one?",
        "correctAnswer": "Belteshazzar",
        "incorrectAnswers": [
            "Belshazzar",
            "Shadrach",
            "Meshach"
        ],
        "difficulty": 1,
        "type": "mc",
        "categories": [
            "Daniel"
        ],
        "biblicalReference": "Daniel 1:7"
    },
    {
        "question": "The man born blind had to wash in... to be able to see.",
        "correctAnswer": "the pool of Siloam",
        "incorrectAnswers": [
            "the pool of Bethesda",
            "the Jordan",
            "the pool of purification"
        ],
        "difficulty": 3,
        "type": "fitb",
        "categories": [
            "John"
        ],
        "biblicalReference": "John 9: 1-7"
    },
    {
        "question": "In the battle against Egypt, King... of Judah was killed.",
        "correctAnswer": "Josiah",
        "incorrectAnswers": [
            "Amon",
            "Manasseh",
            "Ahaz"
        ],
        "difficulty": 5,
        "type": "fitb",
        "categories": [
            "2 Chronicles"
        ],
        "biblicalReference": "2 Chronicles 35: 20-24"
    },
    {
        "question": "Where did the first Christian church originate?",
        "correctAnswer": "Jerusalem",
        "incorrectAnswers": [
            "Antioch",
            "Philippi",
            "Corinth"
        ],
        "difficulty": 3,
        "type": "mc",
        "categories": [
            "Acts"
        ],
        "biblicalReference": "Acts 2: 40, 41"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who were the third and fourth disciples of Jesus?",
        "correctAnswer": "John and James",
        "incorrectAnswers": [
            "Simon and Andrew",
            "Simon and James",
            "John and Andrew"
        ],
        "difficulty": 5,
        "type": "mc",
        "categories": [],
        "biblicalReference": "Mark 1: 16-20"
    },
    {
        "question": "Elijah, Ahab and the people went to offer sacrifices on Mount...",
        "correctAnswer": "Carmel",
        "incorrectAnswers": [
            "Horeb",
            "Sinai",
            "Tabor"
        ],
        "difficulty": 3,
        "type": "fitb",
        "categories": [
            "1 Kings"
        ],
        "biblicalReference": "1 Kings 18: 20 -40"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the last word in the Bible?",
        "correctAnswer": "Amen",
        "incorrectAnswers": [
            "Comes",
            "Thanks be to God",
            "Blessing"
        ],
        "difficulty": 1,
        "type": "mc",
        "categories": [
            "Revelation"
        ],
        "biblicalReference": "Revelation 22:21"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who heard a great voice from heaven saying, 'Behold, the tabernacle of God is with men, and He will dwell with them'?",
        "correctAnswer": "John",
        "incorrectAnswers": [
            "Peter",
            "James",
            "Jesus himself"
        ],
        "difficulty": 5,
        "type": "mc",
        "categories": [
            "Revelation"
        ],
        "biblicalReference": "Revelation 21:3"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the name of the Rider on the white horse in Revelation?",
        "correctAnswer": "Faithful and True",
        "incorrectAnswers": [
            "Savior",
            "Christ Jesus",
            "Firm and sure"
        ],
        "difficulty": 5,
        "type": "mc",
        "categories": [
            "Revelation"
        ],
        "biblicalReference": "Revelation 19:11"
    },
    {
        "question": "Complete the sentence: Woe, woe, the great city..., the mighty city",
        "correctAnswer": "Babylon",
        "incorrectAnswers": [
            "Jericho",
            "Jerusalem",
            "Nineveh"
        ],
        "difficulty": 5,
        "type": "fitb",
        "categories": [
            "Revelation"
        ],
        "biblicalReference": "Revelation 18:10"
    },
    {
        "question": "How many times was the trumpet blown in Revelation?",
        "correctAnswer": "7 times",
        "incorrectAnswers": [
            "7 times 70 times",
            "70 times",
            "700 times"
        ],
        "difficulty": 5,
        "type": "mc",
        "categories": [
            "Revelation"
        ],
        "biblicalReference": "Revelation 8, 9, 10, 11"
    },
    {
        "question": "How many seals are opened in Revelation?",
        "correctAnswer": "7",
        "incorrectAnswers": [
            "8",
            "6",
            "3"
        ],
        "difficulty": 5,
        "type": "mc",
        "categories": [
            "Revelation"
        ],
        "biblicalReference": "Revelation 6, 7, 8"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who alone could open the book with the 7 seals?",
        "correctAnswer": "The Lamb",
        "incorrectAnswers": [
            "The Rock",
            "The monster with 7 eyes",
            "No one"
        ],
        "difficulty": 5,
        "type": "mc",
        "categories": [
            "Revelation"
        ],
        "biblicalReference": "Revelation 5"
    },
    {
        "question": "What was in the Letter of Christ to Sardis?",
        "correctAnswer": "You have a name that you are alive, but you are dead",
        "incorrectAnswers": [
            "Woe to you",
            "The rules that that church had to follow",
            "To you is Eternal Life"
        ],
        "difficulty": 5,
        "type": "mc",
        "categories": [
            "Revelation"
        ],
        "biblicalReference": "Revelation 3:1"
    },
    {
        "question": "Where did John write the book of Revelation?",
        "correctAnswer": "On the island of Patmos",
        "incorrectAnswers": [
            "In prison",
            "John did not write Revelation",
            "In the wilderness"
        ],
        "difficulty": 1,
        "type": "mc",
        "categories": [
            "Revelation"
        ],
        "biblicalReference": "Revelation 1:9"
    },
    {
        "question": "What did Jude warn against in his book of the Bible?",
        "correctAnswer": "Against false teachers",
        "incorrectAnswers": [
            "Against the devil",
            "Against sin",
            "Against the world"
        ],
        "difficulty": 3,
        "type": "mc",
        "categories": [
            "Jude"
        ],
        "biblicalReference": "Jude 1"
    },
    {
        "question": "To whom did John write his letter, 3 John?",
        "correctAnswer": "Gaius",
        "incorrectAnswers": [
            "The church of Laodicea",
            "To no one in particular",
            "To Diotrephes"
        ],
        "difficulty": 5,
        "type": "mc",
        "categories": [
            "3 John"
        ],
        "biblicalReference": "3 John 1:1"
    },
    {
        "question": "From what place did John write his letter, 2 John?",
        "correctAnswer": "From Ephesus",
        "incorrectAnswers": [
            "From Corinth",
            "From Asia Minor",
            "That is unknown"
        ],
        "difficulty": 3,
        "type": "mc",
        "categories": [
            "John"
        ],
        "biblicalReference": "2 John"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which prophet told King Hezekiah that he was to die?",
        "correctAnswer": "Isaiah",
        "incorrectAnswers": [
            "Jeremiah",
            "Micah",
            "Amos"
        ],
        "difficulty": 3,
        "type": "mc",
        "categories": [
            "Isaiah"
        ],
        "biblicalReference": "Isaiah 38:1"
    },
    {
        "question": "Whose ear did Peter cut off?",
        "correctAnswer": "Malchus",
        "incorrectAnswers": [
            "Matthew",
            "Maltus",
            "Caiaphas"
        ],
        "difficulty": 1,
        "type": "mc",
        "categories": [
            "John"
        ],
        "biblicalReference": "John 18:10"
    },
    {
        "question": "What did the Macedonian man ask in Paul's dream?",
        "correctAnswer": "'Come over to Macedonia and help us'",
        "incorrectAnswers": [
            "'Come over and help us'",
            "'Come and see'",
            "'Come over to Macedonia and preach the gospel'"
        ],
        "difficulty": 3,
        "type": "mc",
        "categories": [
            "Acts"
        ],
        "biblicalReference": "Acts 19: 9, 10"
    },
    {
        "question": "What punishment did the prophet Elijah announce for King Ahab?",
        "correctAnswer": "There will be no dew or rain",
        "incorrectAnswers": [
            "There will be no more rain",
            "There will be a famine",
            "Many people will die"
        ],
        "difficulty": 3,
        "type": "mc",
        "categories": [
            "1 Kings"
        ],
        "biblicalReference": "1 Kings 17:1"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who was Samuel's father?",
        "correctAnswer": "Elkanah",
        "incorrectAnswers": [
            "Elihu",
            "Elam",
            "Jeroboam"
        ],
        "difficulty": 1,
        "type": "mc",
        "categories": [
            "1 Samuel"
        ],
        "biblicalReference": "1 Samuel 1:1"
    },
    {
        "question": "In which city did Paul speak of the unknown God?",
        "correctAnswer": "In Athens",
        "incorrectAnswers": [
            "In Corinth",
            "In Philippi",
            "In Thyatira"
        ],
        "difficulty": 3,
        "type": "mc",
        "categories": [
            "Acts",
            "Romans"
        ],
        "biblicalReference": "Acts 17:23"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who went with Paul and Barnabas on their first missionary journey?",
        "correctAnswer": "John Mark",
        "incorrectAnswers": [
            "Mark",
            "John",
            "Peter"
        ],
        "difficulty": 3,
        "type": "mc",
        "categories": [
            "Acts"
        ],
        "biblicalReference": "Acts 13"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who were the sons of Zebedee?",
        "correctAnswer": "James and John",
        "incorrectAnswers": [
            "John and Andrew",
            "Andrew and Peter",
            "James and Peter"
        ],
        "difficulty": 3,
        "type": "mc",
        "categories": [],
        "biblicalReference": "Mark 1: 19 , 20"
    },
    {
        "question": "In what place was David proclaimed king?",
        "correctAnswer": "Hebron",
        "incorrectAnswers": [
            "Jerusalem",
            "Judah",
            "Gilead"
        ],
        "difficulty": 3,
        "type": "mc",
        "categories": [
            "2 Kings"
        ],
        "biblicalReference": "2 Kings 2:4"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who said: 'You almost persuade me to become a Christian'?",
        "correctAnswer": "King Agrippa",
        "incorrectAnswers": [
            "Silas",
            "Governor Felix",
            "King David"
        ],
        "difficulty": 1,
        "type": "mc",
        "categories": [
            "Acts"
        ],
        "biblicalReference": "Acts 26:28"
    },
    {
        "question": "During the journey through the wilderness, the water was bitter at...",
        "correctAnswer": "Marah",
        "incorrectAnswers": [
            "Elim",
            "Rephidim",
            "Kadesh Barnea"
        ],
        "difficulty": 1,
        "type": "fitb",
        "categories": [],
        "biblicalReference": "Exodus 15:23"
    },
    {
        "question": "What idolatry did King Jeroboam introduce?",
        "correctAnswer": "The worship of the golden calves",
        "incorrectAnswers": [
            "The worship of Baal",
            "The worship of Astarte",
            "The worship of the stars"
        ],
        "difficulty": 3,
        "type": "mc",
        "categories": [
            "1 Kings"
        ],
        "biblicalReference": "1 Kings 12: 25-33"
    },
    {
        "question": "How many missionary journeys did Paul make?",
        "correctAnswer": "3",
        "incorrectAnswers": [
            "2",
            "4",
            "5"
        ],
        "difficulty": 1,
        "type": "mc",
        "categories": [
            "Acts"
        ],
        "biblicalReference": "Acts"
    },
    {
        "question": "On what mountain was the Ascension of Jesus?",
        "correctAnswer": "Mount of Olives",
        "incorrectAnswers": [
            "Horeb",
            "Moriah",
            "Nebo"
        ],
        "difficulty": 1,
        "type": "mc",
        "categories": [
            "Acts"
        ],
        "biblicalReference": "Acts 1: 9-12"
    },
    {
        "question": "Where did Jesus' mother live?",
        "correctAnswer": "Nazareth",
        "incorrectAnswers": [
            "Bethlehem",
            "Jerusalem",
            "That is unknown"
        ],
        "difficulty": 1,
        "type": "mc",
        "categories": [
            "Luke"
        ],
        "biblicalReference": "Luke 1:26"
    },
    {
        "question": "How many days are there between Ascension and Pentecost?",
        "correctAnswer": "10",
        "incorrectAnswers": [
            "40",
            "3",
            "12"
        ],
        "difficulty": 1,
        "type": "mc",
        "categories": [
            "Pentecost",
            "Ascension"
        ],
        "biblicalReference": "Acts 1 and 2"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who was the first Christian to die for his faith?",
        "correctAnswer": "Stephen",
        "incorrectAnswers": [
            "Peter",
            "James",
            "Philip"
        ],
        "difficulty": 1,
        "type": "mc",
        "categories": [
            "Acts"
        ],
        "biblicalReference": "Acts 7: 54-60"
    },
    {
        "question": "Blessed is the man who does not... in the counsel of the wicked",
        "correctAnswer": "walk",
        "incorrectAnswers": [
            "run",
            "stand",
            "go"
        ],
        "difficulty": 1,
        "type": "fitb",
        "categories": [
            "Psalms"
        ],
        "biblicalReference": "Psalm 1:1"
    }
]
